<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
File: font.xml
Description:
This is a component type description for the font manager. It contains default
information for a font type manager and acts as a template for managers created
in a type of publication. This information goes in the project configuration.

Todo:
1) Need to connect to an external DTD, schema, whatever for validation.

-->


<root>

    <section>
        <name>TeX Settings</name>
        <sectionID>TexSettings</sectionID>
        <description>Settings for this font as used by a TeX rendering system in this publication project.</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Font Size Unit</name>
            <description>Using a value in points (pt), this scales the font size of all elements according to the amount of the value. 1pt is equal to 100%. Example, to decrease the size by 5%, enter the value .095pt. Default = 1pt</description>
            <key>fontSizeUnit</key>
            <type>integer</type>
            <value>[function:getFontSizeUnit]</value>
            <texCode>\FontSizeUnit=[val]pt</texCode>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Line Spacing Factor</name>
            <description>Scaling factor used to adjust line spacing (leading), relative to font size.</description>
            <key>lineSpacingFactor</key>
            <type>integer</type>
            <value>[function:getLineSpacingFactor]</value>
            <texCode>\def\LineSpacingFactor{[val]}</texCode>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Vertical Space Factor</name>
            <description>Scaling factor used to adjust amount of vertical spaces applied for USFM style sheet SpaceBefore and SpaceAfter values.</description>
            <key>verticalSpaceFactor</key>
            <type>integer</type>
            <value>1</value>
            <texCode>\def\VerticalSpaceFactor{[val]}</texCode>
        </setting>
    </section>

    <section>
        <name>General Settings</name>
        <sectionID>GeneralSettings</sectionID>
        <description>General settings for this font used in this publication project.</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Use Rendering System</name>
            <key>useRenderingSystem</key>
            <description>The font rendering system (abbreviation) that will be used, e.g. use \"GR\" for Graphite. The supplied font rendering system must be supported by the font, otherwise the field should remain empty. (Note: Because of a bug in XeTeX, the current rendering engine, the default is set to GR. This may not be appropreate for all fonts.) </description>
            <type>string</type>
            <value>GR</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Use Feature</name>
            <key>useFeature</key>
            <description>List any features needed for this font to render correctly. One or more can be listed, each must be separated by a colon.</description>
            <type>string</type>
            <value></value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Use Language</name>
            <key>useLanguage</key>
            <description>The language this font will be working with. Specify the language by using its three letter Ethnologue code. The language must be supported by the font, otherwise the field should remain empty.</description>
            <type>string</type>
            <value></value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Use Font Mappings</name>
            <key>useMapping</key>
            <description>The name of the font mapping file you wish to use. Only one file per component type can be used.</description>
            <type>string</type>
            <value></value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Footnote Caller Font</name>
            <key>fnCallerFont</key>
            <description>Footnote caller characters are normally taken from the default (body text) font. If an alternate (installed) font is specified here, that font will be used for the caller character(s).</description>
            <type>string</type>
            <value></value>
        </setting>
    
    </section>

</root>

