<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<!--
File: format_values.xml
Description:
This contains all the format values for a publication.

Todo:
1) Need to connect to an external DTD, schema, whatever for validation.

-->


<root>
    <section>
        <name>General Settings</name>
        <sectionID>GeneralSettings</sectionID>
        <description>This contains general format settings for this publication.</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Measurement Unit</name>
            <key>MeasurementUnit</key>
            <description>The unit of measurement used in this publication.</description>
            <type>string</type>
            <value>mm</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Source Encoding Transform</name>
            <description>In the case of multi-script projects or non-Unicode, an encoding transformation may be needed make the source data useful to the system.  The encoding information is stored in the Encoding section and should be the same as other files used in this project.   Default = False</description>
            <key>sourceEncodeTransform</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>True</value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Chapter and Verse</name>
        <sectionID>ChapterVerse</sectionID>
        <description>Parameters that cover varous aspects of formating of chapter and verse layout</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Short Book Chapter Omit</name>
            <key>shortBookChapterOmit</key>
            <description>If a book consists of a single chapter it is often desirable to not have a chapter number marking the beginning of the book.  If set True, this will insert a command in the control file to prevent inserting the chapter number in a single chapter book.  Default = True</description>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>True</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Omit All Chapter Numbers</name>
            <description>Omit all the chapter numbers in the book. (Actually this is what is done for one-chapter books.)  If set to true, this will override the Short Book Chapter Omit setting that is normally used in one chapter books and will take all the chapter numbers out of all books.  Default = False</description>
            <key>omitAllChapterNumbers</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>False</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Omit Verse Number One</name>
            <description>Setting this to True will prevent verse number 1 from being displayed which is normally good for in-line verse formated Bibles that use drop chapter numbers.  Default = True</description>
            <key>omitVerseNumberOne</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>False</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Chapter Verse Separator</name>
            <description>Change the default c/v separator character or adjust the space by adding some extra code.  For example, to kern the space between the separator character you could enter: "\kern.02em:\kern.02em".  This setting primary affects the header reference. Default = ":"</description>
            <key>chapterVerseSeparator</key>
            <type>string</type>
            <value>\kern.1em:\kern.1em</value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Columns</name>
        <sectionID>Columns</sectionID>
        <description>Parameters which have to do with column layout for Scripture publications</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Title Columns</name>
            <description>Number of columns used to typeset the main title.   Default = 1</description>
            <key>titleColumns</key>
            <type>integer</type>
            <value>1</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Intro Columns</name>
            <description>Number of columns used to typeset introduction material.  Introduction material is defined by USFM markers beginning with \i  Default = 1</description>
            <key>introColumns</key>
            <type>integer</type>
            <value>1</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Body Columns</name>
            <description>Number of columns used to typeset the body text.   Default = 1</description>
            <key>bodyColumns</key>
            <type>integer</type>
            <value>1</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Column Gutter Rule</name>
            <description>Do you want to place a vertical line between the columns in the column gutter?   Default = False</description>
            <key>columnGutterRule</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>True</value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Footnotes</name>
        <sectionID>Footnotes</sectionID>
        <description>This section includes all textual elements that go into footnote area which included both footnotes and cross references.</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Use Auto Callers</name>
            <description>If a symbol (or a csv sequence of symbols) is desired for a caller character, rather than an incremental character(s), set this to true then enter the character you want in the following fields.   Default = True</description>
            <key>useAutoCallers</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>True</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Crossreference Auto Caller Character</name>
            <description>Define a character or sequence in this field to enable the use of auto callers in your text.  You can even add kerning control as well as in the examples By setting something in this field you will override the autoCallerStartChar setting.   A sequence = *,+,¶,§,**,++,¶¶,§§   Use only an asterisk = *   Kern an asterisk = \kern0.2em*\kern0.4em   Raise an asterisk = \raise .8em\hbox{*}   Raise and kern = \raise .8em\hbox{\kern0.2em*}   Default = *</description>
            <key>crossrefAutoCallerCharacter</key>
            <type>string</type>
            <value></value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Numeric Callers (Footnotes)</name>
        <sectionID>NumericCallers</sectionID>
        <description>Set to true to use numeric callers on footnotes instead of alphabetic callers.   Default = FalseseNumericCallersFootnotes = false</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Numeric Callers (Crossrefs)</name>
            <description>Use numeric callers on cross references instead of alphabetic callers.   Default = False</description>
            <key>useNumericCallersCrossrefs</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>False</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Page Reset Callers (Footnotes)</name>
            <description>Restart numbering or character sequence for footnotes on each page.   Default = False</description>
            <key>pageResetCallersFootnotes</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>False</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Page Reset Callers (Crossrefs)</name>
            <description>Restart numbering or character sequence for cross references on each page.   Default = False</description>
            <key>pageResetCallersCrossrefs</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>False</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Omit Caller In Footnotes</name>
            <description>To omit caller characters from the footnotes at the bottom of the page.   Default = True</description>
            <key>omitCallerInFootnotes</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>True</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Omit Caller In Crossrefs</name>
            <description>To omit caller characters from the cross references at the bottom of the page.   Default = True</description>
            <key>omitCallerInCrossrefs</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>False</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Paragraphed Footnotes</name>
            <description>Output the footnotes on the bottom of the page in paragraph format rather than one line for each one.   Default = True</description>
            <key>paragraphedFootnotes</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>True</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Paragraphed Crossrefs</name>
            <description>Output the crossrefs on the bottom of the page in paragraph format rather than one line for each one.   Default = True</description>
            <key>paragraphedCrossrefs</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>False</value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Header and Footer</name>
        <sectionID>HeaderFooter</sectionID>
        <description>Header/Footer settings in this section</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Use Running Header Rule</name>
            <description>If this is set to true a rule will be placed in the header according to the Running Header Rule Position.   Default = False</description>
            <key>useRunningHeaderRule</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>False</value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Footer Content</name>
        <sectionID>FooterContent</sectionID>
        <description>Footer Configuration, leave them empty if you don't want anything to show up in the footer, like page numbers on the title page.  The default is leave them all empty.  Normally we do not want to put any content in the footer as it takes up an extra line which addes up to extra pages in a publication.  It is more efficient to put information like page numbers in the running header.</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Use Running Footer</name>
            <description>Set this to true if you want to have a running footer line in your document. (Defalt = False)</description>
            <key>useRunningFooter</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>False</value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Header Content</name>
        <sectionID>HeaderContent</sectionID>
        <description>Information to include in the running header (at top of pages, except first) We set the items to print at left/center/right of odd and even pages separately   Possible contents:      \bookname = the name of the book as defined in \h      \rangeref = Scripture reference of the range of text on the page;      \firstref = reference of the first verse on the page)      \lastref = reference of the last verse on the page)      \pagenumber = the page number      \empty = print nothing in this position To follow are each of the individual position.</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Use Running Header</name>
            <description>Set this to true if you want to have a running header line in your document. (Defalt = True)</description>
            <key>useRunningHeader</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>True</value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Hyphenation</name>
        <sectionID>Hyphenation</sectionID>
        <description>Some information for building TeX commands for building the hyphenation control file and other related files located in the project's hyphenation folder.  Some file names are stored in this section.  These are not used in the makefile process and can vary depending on how the process is run.  Note: remember to re-make/overwrite the current TeX Hyphenation file for the changes to take effect.</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Use Hyphenation</name>
            <description>Set to true to use hyphenation in the project.  Hyphenation is important to any project but it needs to be setup before it can be used.  Therefore the default is false Default = False</description>
            <key>useHyphenation</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>True</value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Ilustrations</name>
        <sectionID>Ilustrations</sectionID>
        <description>Illustration resources</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Use Illustrations</name>
            <description>Illustrations - If set to true this will allow the system to put in place all the files necessary to have illustrations used in this publication.  One warning, however, if you choose to set this to false after once using illustrations, it will delete all the illustration related files with the exception of the captions.csv file.  This is to prevent errors from occurring during the typesetting process.  Default = False</description>
            <key>useIllustrations</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>True</value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Page Layout</name>
        <sectionID>PageLayout</sectionID>
        <description>Page layout information.  This covers general page layout format options.</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Custom Page Height</name>
            <description>This is the height of the page after it has been printed and trimmed to its final size. Default = 210mm (A5)</description>
            <key>customPageHeight</key>
            <type>integer</type>
            <value></value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Custom Page Width</name>
            <description>This is the width of the page after it has been printed and trimmed to its final size. Default = 148mm (A5)</description>
            <key>customPageWidth</key>
            <type>integer</type>
            <value></value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Page Size ID Code</name>
            <description>If you are using a common page size please enter the standard code.  If a custom size is being used just enter "custom". Default = A5</description>
            <key>pageSizeCode</key>
            <type>string</type>
            <value>A5</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Starting Page Number</name>
            <description>Sometimes the content should not start with the default page number of '1'. If a number is set in this field, the macro will insert a \pageno command in the control file.  Note this is for the main content section only.  Individual components in the front and back matter must have the \pageno command inserted manually into their control files.   Default = Null (which means no command output, page starts on '1')</description>
            <key>pageNumberBegin</key>
            <type>integer</type>
            <value></value>
        </setting>
    </section>
    <section>
        <name>Text Elements</name>
        <sectionID>TextElements</sectionID>
        <description>General settings for text level elements</description>
        <setting>
            <name>Justify Paragraphs</name>
            <description>Paragraphs are justified by default.  Set this to false to turn off justification.   Default = True</description>
            <key>justifyParagraphs</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>True</value>
        </setting>
        <setting>
            <name>Right To Left</name>
            <description>Uncomment to use right-to-left text layout mode   Default = False</description>
            <key>rightToLeft</key>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <value>False</value>
        </setting>
    </section>
</root>

